<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shengyao Zhuang | Hang Li, Ph.D Student in UQ</title>
    <link>https://hangli.me/author/shengyao-zhuang/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://hangli.me/author/shengyao-zhuang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Shengyao Zhuang</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:28:45 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://hangli.me/images/icon_hu3004b989a6c4142912b7cfdd252613aa_18546_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Shengyao Zhuang</title>
      <link>https://hangli.me/author/shengyao-zhuang/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Deep Query Likelihood Model for Information Retrieval</title>
      <link>https://hangli.me/publication/ecir2021-deep-qlm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:28:45 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hangli.me/publication/ecir2021-deep-qlm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The query likelihood model (QLM) for information retrieval has been thoroughly investigated and utilised. At the basis of this method is the representation of queries and documents as language models; then retrieval corresponds to evaluate the likelihood that the query could be generated by the document. Several approaches have arisen to compute such probability, including by maximum likelihood, smoothing and considering translation probabilities from related terms.
In this paper, we consider estimating this likelihood using modern pre-trained deep language models, and in particular the text-to-text transfer transformer (T5) &amp;ndash; giving rise to the QLM-T5. This approach is evaluated on the passage ranking task of the MS MARCO dataset; empirical results show that QLM-T5 significantly outperforms traditional QLM methods, as well as a recent ad-hoc methods that exploits T5 for this task.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UQ IElab at TREC 2020 CAsT Track</title>
      <link>https://hangli.me/publication/treccast2020-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:28:45 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://hangli.me/publication/treccast2020-overview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper describes the work done by the IELAB for the TREC Conversational Assistance Track (CAsT) 2020. IELAB investigated two methods to improve both the retrieval and re-ranking stages of a conversational IR system.
The first method used an Adapted Query (AQ), which extracted context from the first utterance only to expand all subsequent queries for a conversational session. The second method utilized a query likelihood model (QLM) which used a pre-trained deep language model to estimate the likelihood that a query could be generated by a document.
Specifically, we used the text-to-text transfer transformer (T5) as a scoring functions for re-ranking passages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
